# 哈喽 大家好
Hello everyone
# 今天跟大家分享一个汤
Today I’ll share a soup with you
# 就是番茄泡蛋汤
Which is the “Tomato and Fried Egg Soup”
# 我们这边说的这个泡蛋汤
In our dialect, it has a different name
# 其实就是煎蛋汤
But it’s the same thing
# 然后番茄蛋汤其实够简单的了
The regular “Tomato and Egg Drops Soup” is so simple
# 然后就是分享一些不一样的做法
So I’ll share a version with a twist to it
# 我们看这个番茄新不新鲜
Let’s see how fresh these tomatoes are
# 就是看这个位置
By looking here
# 这个（蒂）还是绿色的
The vines are still green
# 我们切这个番茄的时候
When we are dicing the tomatoes
# 中间这个（蒂）最好是把它去掉
We'd better remove the core
# 先从中间切开
First cut it in half
# 然后左边一刀 右边一刀
Then slice from the left and right
# 这样子它就下来了
It’ll be off like this
# 我们切这个番茄
For the tomatoes today
# 这次我们切厚一点
Cut them into thicker slices
# 切厚一点就是让它中间有足够的汁水
Thicker slices are juicier
# 待会儿煮了之后
Later during cooking,
# 这个汁水就不会流出来
The juice won’t come out
# 不会流失
It will be contained
# 吃的时候感觉饱满比较多汁
Then it will have a juicier taste and fuller texture
# 别看一个简简单单的一个番茄蛋汤
Even though it’s only a simple soup
# 这中间有很多的小技巧
It still has a lot of culinary tricks
# 然后我们来打鸡蛋
Then let’s mix the eggs
# 然后我们这个鸡蛋打的时候
When we are mixing the eggs
# 尽量的把这个鸡蛋给它蛋液挑起来
Try to use a full range of motion
# 让空气进去
To incorporate more air
# 这样子煎出来蛋才够嫩
Then the fried eggs will taste softer
# 把这个蛋液挑起来
Lift the egg mixture up like this
# 空气进去之后这个蛋液里面会有很多小气泡
When the air is mixed in, there will be many bubbles
# 我们一般在酒店里面做的话
When we make this in restaurants
# 这个蛋液里面要加一点醋 提升它的鲜味
We usually add some vinegar to enhance the umami
# 然后再加一点盐
Then some salt
# 好 我们打好了蛋液你看
Alright, it’s done
# 非常多的小气泡
Lots of bubbles inside
# 这就说明蛋液打的比较成功
Success
# 最后我们切点这个葱花
Finally let’s chop some green onions
# 好 准备开始整
Alright, let’s make the soup
# 首先我们把锅烧热
First we heat up the wok
# 然后加入一大勺植物油滑锅
Add a ladle of vegetable oil to grease the wok
# 同学们煎蛋必须事先烧热油滑锅
Preheating and greasing the wok are required for frying eggs
# 不然煎蛋很容易粘锅
Otherwise the eggs stick very easily
# 然后加入蛋液三分之一的油
Then add oil, about 1/3 the volume of the egg mixture
# 油温烧热之后先用炒勺盛出一些
After the oil is heated, scoop some out with a ladle
# 蛋液下锅之后再把烧热的油重新淋在蛋液上面
Add in the beaten eggs, then pour the heated oil over the eggs
# 这样可以让蛋液双面受热均匀
So that the eggs are cooked evenly from both sides
# 然后转中火把鸡蛋煎香
Turn the heat to medium and keep frying the egg
# 中途再翻过来煎另外一面
Flip the eggs halfway through
# 鸡蛋煎香之后把切好的西红柿下锅翻炒几下
Once the eggs’ aroma comes out, add in the tomatoes. Stir fry for a bit
# 然后加入事先准备好的开水
Then pour in some boiling water
# 同学们加开水烧汤更容易把汤烧白
The boiling water makes the soup whiter
# 大火烧开之后转中火烧3分钟
Bring it to a boil over high heat, then turn down to medium heat and boil for 3 minutes
# 中途再撇去多余的浮沫
Skim off the scum
# 蛋汤烧白之后再加入适量的盐调味
When the soup becomes white, season with salt
# 最后撒上葱花即可出锅
Sprinkle with some chopped green onions and it’s done
# 来 我给你舀四伯爷
Uncle, let me get you some
# 要的呀
Alrighty
# 舀点蛋汤 先喝点汤
Get some soup first
# 要的
Alright
# 你吃番茄不
You want tomatoes?
# 可以可以
Sure
# 来2片番茄
A few slices of tomatoes
# 番茄咬得动
The tomatoes are pretty soft
# 饭前先喝汤
Have some soup before the meal
# 这个番茄粉嘟嘟的噶
The tomatoes look cute
# 诶呀 刚烧起来的好烫哦
Hot hot hot
# 慢点嘛
Slow down then
# 肯定了四伯爷
Of course uncle
# 你饿了呀
You hungry, huh?
# 这个汤肯定有点烫
The soup must be pretty hot
# 我先尝一下什么味道
Let me taste
# 好吃
Nice
# 这个蛋香味特别浓
The aroma of the eggs is very strong
# 我们这个鸡蛋煎的时候不要把它搅碎
Don’t break the eggs during stir frying
# 就两边煎到它泡起来了之后
Just wait for both sides to get fluffy
# 然后再放番茄下去炒一下再放水
Stir fry with tomatoes and pour water in
# 如果你们家里面火小的话
If your burner is weak
# 可以事先准备好开水
Remember to boil the water before hand
# 这个汤很好喝噶
The soup is nice
# 我们这个的话就是保持
We are trying to keep…
# 这个汤很鲜
The soup is really savory
# 你还没放味精都这么好喝
It’s so good even without MSG
# 嗯
Yeah
# 这个番茄我们就是保持里面的原汁原味
We are trying to keep the original flavor of the tomatoes
# 所以就可以切厚一些
So keep the slices a little thicker
# 可以
Nice
# 如果大家想吃那个番茄蛋花汤的话
If you want the “Tomato Egg Drop Soup”
# 就正好跟这个相反
It will be exactly the opposite
# 切得越薄就越好
The thinner tomato slices, the better
# 因为更容易熟透
Because thinner slices are easier to cook
# 然后就是用开水冲一下就可以了
Just add some boiling water and it would be done
# 好了 本期视频就到这里
Alright, that’s it for this episode
# 你们要是对这个感兴趣的话可以尝（试）一下
Try on your own if you are interested!